<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Martian Sapiens]]></title><description><![CDATA[Lets Colonize Mars Together]]></description><link>https://martiansapiens.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 19:28:11 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Why It Has to Be On Colonizing Mars?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello Martian Sapiens! It will be about colonizing Mars. Below I wrote the why. In case you prefer to listen here you have the recording…]]></description><link>https://martiansapiens.com/2020-03-14/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://martiansapiens.com/2020-03-14/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello &lt;a href=&quot;https://martiansapiens.com/&quot;&gt;Martian Sapiens&lt;/a&gt;! It will be about colonizing Mars. Below I wrote &lt;strong&gt;the why&lt;/strong&gt;. In case you prefer to listen here you have the recording:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&apos;https://www.youtalky.xyz/player/hf&apos; title=&apos;YouTalky.com - Player&apos; width=&apos;100%&apos; style=&apos;border: 0;&apos;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks &amp;#x26; Shoutout to the Reddit community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://hvitis.dev/how-to-start-developing-a-game-like-stardew-valley-using-monogames-xna&quot;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/gamedev/comments/m15z2a/inspired_by_the_concernedapes_stardew_valley_i/&quot;&gt;gamedev reddit&lt;/a&gt; and received a heartwarming welcoming! 🤗 I did not expected such a great people there. Usually on different reddits there is 1 or 2 people so.. thank you 🙏&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to your suggestions I have created a &lt;strong&gt;subreddit&lt;/strong&gt; for this purposes here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/martianSapiens&quot;&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/martianSapiens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main goal is to let joy of creativity power learning skills. Let’s learn together. I will be posting interesting information about Mars and other stuff since I want this game to embed set of &lt;strong&gt;real rules&lt;/strong&gt;. You can brainstorm with me as ideas surge together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/hubo/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hubo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; suggested that I &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/derek_sivers_keep_your_goals_to_yourself?language=en&quot;&gt;should not let others know&lt;/a&gt; about my goals. I don’t. I do not know the finale of this, where it leads me but those words here, is already working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The truths you cannot omit - Earth Rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A game, with a sets of rules. Rules that are unbreakable and rules that are soft - conventions. The unbreakable rules is harsh physics we don’t always get. I - for instance - find difficult to comprehend time relativity. How the fact that &lt;em&gt;astronauts on the orbit age more slowly due to their high orbital speed&lt;/em&gt; affects our lives?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the educational delay - knowledge on a lot of laws we know do not propagate to millions of people (at least not as fast and profound as we would like). Theory of evolution, genome, fiat money. Most people are not aware of the knowledge that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NNnIGh9g6fA&amp;#x26;list=PL848F2368C90DDC3D&quot;&gt;literally explains their behavior&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that we on Earth play by one rule that is called money. Gold naturally became as a mean of exchange because it was &lt;a href=&quot;https://mises.org/library/history-money-and-banking-united-states-colonial-era-world-war-ii&quot;&gt;the most scarce and lasting material&lt;/a&gt; known to us. We basically were saving our time in an ore. We still do. The visible, touchable things was our currency for most of the time. Now we advanced it a level higher, we use magnetic discs and electricity to store and compute money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generating &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2021/01/14/politics/biden-economic-rescue-package-coronavirus-stimulus/index.html&quot;&gt;trillions of papers&lt;/a&gt; (or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mrjoElG8KGI&quot;&gt;once and zeros&lt;/a&gt;) is just like using hacks in a big MMORPG. There are some out there who have access to hacks and get full backpacks of dollars literally after clicking enter. All others have to “farm like noobs” - which is work in a normal job or grinding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grinding that’s been recently popular - it can be learning some &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s4LQTp-fhuo&quot;&gt;useless skills&lt;/a&gt; in order to get 1 tiny drop of that fake money. It can be learning &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/wallstreetbets/&quot;&gt;more complicated skills&lt;/a&gt; to get more drops of that same, fake money. The problem is that you can buy a real brain surgery with fake money. But.. it means that redistributing trillions of dollars (collective time and efforts) could do good things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you seen all those wonders done by bankers and politicians? If so, let me know in the comments. Maybe I will change my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Life is a game and I got bored playing it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like you are exping in a nice, farming place and a hacker comes and kills all of them with one hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 15px -30px !important max-width: 700px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 55.99999999999999%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAALABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwAAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIEAf/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAID/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAFiKwNDSkP/xAAZEAACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAgAQEjH/2gAIAQEAAQUC7AwzmIx2K//EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAEf/aAAgBAwEBPwHZG//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAR/9oACAECAQE/AYf/xAAZEAACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAARAhMTL/2gAIAQEABj8CrB1qOWK5/8QAHBABAAEEAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQABITGRQXHR/9oACAEBAAE/IVDO4geBl3pByJgdy9Oa7n//2gAMAwEAAgADAAAAEDQ//8QAGBEAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERodH/2gAIAQMBAT8Qb0Ydmvh//8QAGBEAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERQaH/2gAIAQIBAT8QsTm8P//EABwQAQADAAIDAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExQVFxgf/aAAgBAQABPxAKaQsTgHWQ6Xewe/lkbLWfYgdGxFsg3ZoxsFEDL8p//9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;MapleStory Hacker&quot;
        title=&quot;MapleStory Hacker&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/4dcaf0b35f797e02b69d1c290fb4e018/29d31/maple-story-hacker.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/4dcaf0b35f797e02b69d1c290fb4e018/e52aa/maple-story-hacker.jpg 175w,
/static/4dcaf0b35f797e02b69d1c290fb4e018/70ebb/maple-story-hacker.jpg 350w,
/static/4dcaf0b35f797e02b69d1c290fb4e018/29d31/maple-story-hacker.jpg 700w,
/static/4dcaf0b35f797e02b69d1c290fb4e018/72e01/maple-story-hacker.jpg 1024w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;pic1: Maple Story Hacker killing all mobs at once.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get annoyed, change map or spot and continue playing. It’s fine. The problem is that the hacker is still cheating and later when you go to a marketplace, you will see prices given by him. It’s still fine, you can just change a game or play a singleplayer. &lt;strong&gt;You can’t do that in real life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if we assume that we live in a simulation or Matrix, we don’t know how to disconnect and play the singleplayer (besides, the biggest fun is to play together!). The only singleplayer I can imagine is the one with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2TWYDogv4WQ&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wilson the volleyball&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and it does not look like fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a common goal, shared understanding, with billions of players and thousands of very powerful hackers (which we can’t even ban from the game) I must say, that playing over the current rules got totally meaningless. I am not saying it’s pointless!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still real value in small percentage of today’s economy and people still believe in the paper. Pursuing the money to some extend is necessary, we all need it for survival. We all are (at least) a set of bio-hardware that emerged from the code (the body that is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://berthub.eu/articles/posts/what-is-life/&quot;&gt;outcome of the code&lt;/a&gt;) thus as organisms we need to fulfill &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Maslow%27s_hierarchy_of_needs&quot;&gt;the basic rules&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I see in hackers that waste collective efforts in the real world is that it decreases amount of creativity that exist in the world. If people have to struggle more to stay afloat or fulfill basic needs it stops them from dreaming. Nikola Tesla said:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Invention is the most important product of creative brain. Be creative is to achieve mastery over the material world. This is the difficult task of the inventor who is often misunderstood and unrewarded. But he finds ample compensation in the pleasing exercises of his powers and in the knowledge of being one of that exceptionally privileged class without whom the race would have long ago perished in the bitter struggle against pitiless elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meaninglessness can be filled with creativity. If you can’t fix the world then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_ZCfNAl6DWE&quot;&gt;at least change your reaction&lt;/a&gt;. My reaction to hackers is staying cheerful by being creative. I have a great and meaningful job (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bullshit_Jobs&quot;&gt;in comparsion to some&lt;/a&gt;) that allows me to put some time into creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigating about Mars, about life, respect and values we cherish is more valuable for me than mounting and riding the hustle wave. I believe that the bubble that is being pumped originates in the banking system which originates from the values we cherish. Kind of self perpetuating destruction mode that I am breaking by following &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; way. Charlie Munger says that he and Warren Buffer became rich by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n-4_ONHa_xc&quot;&gt;following basic morality&lt;/a&gt; (and they don’t like the system that is now). He also points to young people &lt;strong&gt;a set of advices which I am going to follow&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do not overspend your income.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live long (at least I will try).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t pity yourself, do not feel resentment, stay cheerful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty simple set of rules that allows you to &lt;strong&gt;just sit own and focus on the development&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is tons of fun in life. There has to be. For me - excitement and joy of being alive must be present. Otherwise I start making life of others more difficult. This journey is the contrary of dull and meaningless. I don’t want to make just another platform, shooter etc. Copying is boring, there is so much to discover! Plus - &lt;strong&gt;imagine a game about colonizing Mars begin played in the future by children born on Mars!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have already travelled there, part of me at least (&lt;a href=&quot;https://mars.nasa.gov/participate/send-your-name/mars2020/&quot;&gt;my name written on a tag&lt;/a&gt; is there). Probably I won’t ever go there but I would love to feel like being there and solving the problems that they will be facing. Now it’s the time to do it! Next post will be just about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine colonizing Mars before actually colonizing Mars? How cool would that be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What all that has to do with Mars?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating my own rules of course!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that in order to make really cool game about Mars’ and our life over there we need to know about life here, on Earth. All what I have said will not be explicitly showed in the game but it should be reflected somehow there. The fact that people focus on pure entertainment makes all games look empty, monotonous. Stardew Valley is great partially because ConcernedApe was concerned enough to stop and think about capitalism and his in-game coins system etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that setting on such a difficult and creative Journey of developing a game has to start somewhere meaningful. Would you like to waste a few years of your life just to do another shooting platform? There is more to life, more to games. Let’s start investigating then!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you have heard about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xP5-iIeKXE8&quot;&gt;Game of Life&lt;/a&gt; made by a computer scientist. He made a set of rules that enable creation of another “life”. People took it to another level and they used the life that those rules create and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xP5-iIeKXE8&quot;&gt;made another Game of Life within it&lt;/a&gt;! It is exactly like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2sEbe9gveN4&quot;&gt;one of Rick and Morty episodes&lt;/a&gt;. The point is: We have power to create. Create new rules of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a set of rules, a game on Mars. Rules embedded in reality. They are different than the one we have on Earth. Atmosphere, gravity, energy (sun). I want to discover some of them and encapsulate them in a form of a video game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings joy. Creativity. The process of discovering, digging up the idea and making it real. Have you ever played a dull, repetitive game, where there was a sidequest, a game machine of some sort, with a minigame better than the main one? That’s how I feel now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let’s move to Mars now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 15px -30px !important max-width: 700px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 50.28571428571429%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAKABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMCBP/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEC/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAHlvmrJYn//xAAZEAEAAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAAIQEjH/2gAIAQEAAQUCBhVmuK9n/8QAFhEBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABES/9oACAEDAQE/Aa0//8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABH/2gAIAQIBAT8BR//EABQQAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACD/2gAIAQEABj8CX//EABwQAAICAgMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABITEQYRFBkf/aAAgBAQABPyFPib2xjt+m0sVFWP/aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQ2x//xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEf/aAAgBAwEBPxC1P//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAR/9oACAECAQE/EIP/xAAcEAEAAgIDAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABESEAMRBBUYH/2gAIAQEAAT8QnMgFxuHeeg33T494Jt+i98QI424BdG8//9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Mars Beauty&quot;
        title=&quot;Mars Beauty&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/b0323cebd09d36df0d8cf12afc3cec34/29d31/mars-beauty.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/b0323cebd09d36df0d8cf12afc3cec34/e52aa/mars-beauty.jpg 175w,
/static/b0323cebd09d36df0d8cf12afc3cec34/70ebb/mars-beauty.jpg 350w,
/static/b0323cebd09d36df0d8cf12afc3cec34/29d31/mars-beauty.jpg 700w,
/static/b0323cebd09d36df0d8cf12afc3cec34/72e01/mars-beauty.jpg 1024w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mars is empty. It makes it perfect. It is a wonderland. Place so distant that no single pirate has ever sailed there. No warship has ever destroyed any of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p4xtO4RBwPs&quot;&gt;native habitants&lt;/a&gt;. It’s empty. It’s far away. It is so big that Romans were calling it Mars - God of War. It requires the most sophisticated science to get there. To colonize, fight the God it used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can’t allow ourselves to go there and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economicshelp.org/blog/7785/concepts/what-happened-to-the-spanish-gold-from-the-incas/&quot;&gt;dig gold&lt;/a&gt;. We need to fight with the God of War - lack of air, atmosphere, sun, sand storms, cold, distance, loneliness. This makes my chin goes up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives me hope!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will need to send our best. People with extraordinary curiosity. Courage. Knowledge. That dedicated all their lives into learning and preparations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not saying that they are the best humans. I am saying that &lt;strong&gt;there&lt;/strong&gt;, they will be the very best of all billions that have ever lived because they will be &lt;strong&gt;the only one present&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gives an opportunity. Here, on earth, we started straightening our back as monkeys. There - on Mars - we will be able to lift our chins as star travellers who did it all by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stepping on Mars is going to be a singularity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever played in any of the alchemy games?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 15px -30px !important max-width: 258px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 75.42857142857143%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAMBBf/EABUBAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAB/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAHkyrBNC//EABgQAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABERIC/9oACAEBAAEFAq7pmuhQSpk//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAwEBPwE//8QAFBEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEP/aAAgBAgEBPwE//8QAGBAAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAExEKH/2gAIAQEABj8CpSsfN//EABsQAQACAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESFBYZHh/9oACAEBAAE/IbmKcO+Snf2H2psrecIqorMHyf/aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQpM//xAAUEQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQ/9oACAEDAQE/ED//xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIf/aAAgBAgEBPxCn/8QAGxABAQACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAREAITFBYcH/2gAIAQEAAT8QDIKlqRe4kotJFebyT7846p3GGm3znDLUO+t4Gl0Zn//Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Alchemy Game&quot;
        title=&quot;Alchemy Game&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/ef6d2e4852dd8cfd782faac693af2abc/53f89/alchemy-game-combine-elements-evolution.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/ef6d2e4852dd8cfd782faac693af2abc/e52aa/alchemy-game-combine-elements-evolution.jpg 175w,
/static/ef6d2e4852dd8cfd782faac693af2abc/53f89/alchemy-game-combine-elements-evolution.jpg 258w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 258px) 100vw, 258px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;pic2: Alchemy game - Combine elements to discover new once.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did it here, in real life. The device you are reading &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; post on (smartphone probably) has been built from 70 elements that are on the periodic table (we have 83 stable that we have discovered).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discovery of the oxygen almost has taken a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acs.org/content/acs/en/education/whatischemistry/landmarks/josephpriestleyoxygen.html&quot;&gt;life of our fellow friend&lt;/a&gt; - real-life-alchemy player. Not mentioning the people that we have forgotten because they died while discovering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the knowledge we accumulated as a specie we will bring with us, to Mars. For us, on Earth - the moment of landing will be like starting a New Game with a manual in hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over thousands of years, people have migrated, created tribes and competed with each other. Now comes the time when we could start fresh. The part where the rules can be partially set by us. We can all become hackers in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.britannica.com/topic/Mars-Roman-god&quot;&gt;fight against God&lt;/a&gt; (Mars).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What rules can we have on Mars?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 15px -30px !important max-width: 700px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 74.85714285714286%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAPABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFgABAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAwAE/8QAFQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAH/2gAMAwEAAhADEAAAASUtAkdL/8QAGRAAAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQIAERIh/9oACAEBAAEFAiMMDY2UjdeUJ//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAR/9oACAEDAQE/AYf/xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQEf/aAAgBAgEBPwGn/8QAGBABAAMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERMSH/2gAIAQEABj8CYrikQx//xAAbEAEAAgMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAABABEhQXExUf/aAAgBAQABPyFKFLIy1k4v4RxbArHZ4bIbwvJ//9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABBM3//EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIf/aAAgBAwEBPxBQ5P/EABYRAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIf/aAAgBAgEBPxACbP/EABsQAQEBAAMBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAERACExQYGh/9oACAEBAAE/EGjnoZbC5X6OcDAB5tc4D2q9/dQ1gLPzvRVZyrn/2Q==&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Mars Surface&quot;
        title=&quot;Mars Surface&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/8e3e548dcd85b14f593efdc232ae9370/29d31/mars-surface.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/8e3e548dcd85b14f593efdc232ae9370/e52aa/mars-surface.jpg 175w,
/static/8e3e548dcd85b14f593efdc232ae9370/70ebb/mars-surface.jpg 350w,
/static/8e3e548dcd85b14f593efdc232ae9370/29d31/mars-surface.jpg 700w,
/static/8e3e548dcd85b14f593efdc232ae9370/4b190/mars-surface.jpg 800w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&apos;https://www.youtalky.xyz/player/if&apos; title=&apos;YouTalky.com - Player&apos; width=&apos;100%&apos; style=&apos;border: 0;&apos;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The civilization built there will look differently depending on &lt;strong&gt;why, how and what&lt;/strong&gt; we choose to do there. In the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ore_resources_on_Mars&quot;&gt;popular marketing book&lt;/a&gt; we learn that it makes sense to &lt;strong&gt;start with Why&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt; do we want to go there? Is it to just be there? Are we as simple as just plankton that enters everywhere just because it can?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we won’t fight over energy resources there - would it be necessary to have money? Time will be always scarce for us so maybe use directly time units instead?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is our goal to build a better society? Or the main goal is to make Mars habitable? It surely is going to be the first goal but &lt;strong&gt;that is a ‘what’, not ‘why’&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will be the currency on Mars? Once the first community becomes self-sufficient and capable of expanding, trade will begin. Would barter be possible?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to sustain life during first hundreds (thousands?) of years when the period of changing atmosphere will take place. Can we make it being dependant all the time to a complex technology?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to initiate biodiversity? Do we have to take all the seeds from Earth? Ecological chains and impacts are &lt;a href=&quot;https://opentextbc.ca/conceptsofbiologyopenstax/chapter/energy-flow-through-ecosystems/&quot;&gt;very intricate&lt;/a&gt;. Can we have them with a &lt;em&gt;human as the only animal?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we going to spread quickly or we will be like a growing pangaea?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can global, starlink, martian communication prevent tribalism if we separate each other a lot?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we going to ship goods from Mars? &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ore_resources_on_Mars&quot;&gt;Ores&lt;/a&gt;? Is the connection between planets really going to be popular when it comes to travelling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are your concerns? What questions would you have regarding this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My secondary questions is how is Mars, how green can it be, what it hides below the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My main curiosity&lt;/strong&gt; is evolving around what we are going to take there within us. How &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_Genome_Project&quot;&gt;our genes&lt;/a&gt;, the facts of being Homo Sapiens will play out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Game - First Draft&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inspiration from Stardew Valley:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌗 Periods, phases. Springs, winters but also sand storms, 🌎 Earth distance phases (for travelling purposes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🌱 Ecology, growing, plants, sustainability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The money is not the goal. You will get more life from having a healthy plant and good atmosphere readings than from having lots of coins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Settlers 4 inspiration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beginning of the game with one Starlink lander in the middle of the map and basic resources to construct base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;♻️ Taking care of the supply, production, ecosystem chains, not of settlers (Martians).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspiration from Ideas and knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eras:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Era of Preparation (by robots for humans)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Era of Colonization (discovery, mining, building)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Era of Sustainability (self-sufficient colony)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Robots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3D Printing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaudians (&lt;a href=&quot;https://hvitis.dev/how-to-make-cheap-dome-with-gaudi-architecture-and-modular-nature&quot;&gt;Gaudi modular Domes&lt;/a&gt;), starting from the very basic materials available and building up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List the basic requirements for the MVP - brainstorm with people interested in the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.getpaint.net/&quot;&gt;pixelated 2D background-game interface&lt;/a&gt; with lander and robots 🤖.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 15px -30px !important max-width: 700px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 114.28571428571428%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAXABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIBA//EABgBAQADAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEAAgME/9oADAMBAAIQAxAAAAHtkxh0dko5I1oD/8QAGRAAAwEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECEBFB/9oACAEBAAEFAjuN8JrPJhDP/8QAFREBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEBH/2gAIAQMBAT8BIf/EABQRAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACD/2gAIAQIBAT8BH//EABUQAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAh/9oACAEBAAY/Amtf/8QAGxAAAwEAAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERITFBcVH/2gAIAQEAAT8hp3KKfGfRDnsNMcIIV27fBt5P/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABBX0H//xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEBH/2gAIAQMBAT8QXGIWf//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQ/9oACAECAQE/EAgoT//EAB0QAQADAQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAEAESExQXFhgZH/2gAIAQEAAT8Q51hZHdo+IOuwXbfg36hoTbU97FTwPZHZHb7KGXAPlNOPyf/Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;img
        class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
        style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
        alt=&quot;Mars Surface Landing Ship&quot;
        title=&quot;Mars Surface Landing Ship&quot;
        src=&quot;/static/7c527b433357efc301a47a68d476706d/29d31/lockheed-martin-mars-lander.jpg&quot;
        srcset=&quot;/static/7c527b433357efc301a47a68d476706d/e52aa/lockheed-martin-mars-lander.jpg 175w,
/static/7c527b433357efc301a47a68d476706d/70ebb/lockheed-martin-mars-lander.jpg 350w,
/static/7c527b433357efc301a47a68d476706d/29d31/lockheed-martin-mars-lander.jpg 700w,
/static/7c527b433357efc301a47a68d476706d/9ecec/lockheed-martin-mars-lander.jpg 1050w,
/static/7c527b433357efc301a47a68d476706d/d165a/lockheed-martin-mars-lander.jpg 1400w,
/static/7c527b433357efc301a47a68d476706d/72000/lockheed-martin-mars-lander.jpg 1794w&quot;
        sizes=&quot;(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px&quot;
      /&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;pic3: Concept art of future landing. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humanmars.net/2017/09/lockheed-martins-mars-lander-concept.html&quot;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How can you be part of this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drop a comment. Recommend a book. If I’m doing something wrong - explain why. Brainstorm with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invite all &lt;a href=&quot;https://martiansapiens.com/&quot;&gt;Martian Sapiens&lt;/a&gt;, let’s colonize Mars together!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell me about your insights and leave a comment on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/martianSapiens&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hvitis_&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- DOCS --&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The birth of the idea.]]></title><description><![CDATA[It landed on Mars 🌕 I was wondering about game development a long time. Since my childhood. I started with the actual idea and described the beginning of it on my original blog. Check out how it all started. Tell me about your insights and leave a comment on Reddit or Twitter Welcome to the new blog, I hope you enjoy your stay! This is an example of how you can control what excerpt shows up.]]></description><link>https://martiansapiens.com/2020-03-10/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://martiansapiens.com/2020-03-10/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;It landed on Mars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🌕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was wondering about game development a long time. Since my childhood. I started with the actual idea and described the beginning of it on my original blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://hvitis.dev/how-to-start-developing-a-game-like-stardew-valley-using-monogames-xna&quot;&gt;how it all started&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tell me about your insights and leave a comment on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/martianSapiens&quot;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hvitis_&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new blog, I hope you enjoy your stay! This is an example of how you can control what excerpt shows up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- end --&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sed urna justo, scelerisque consectetur pharetra vitae, facilisis vel diam. Maecenas auctor enim a volutpat mattis. Morbi sit amet turpis a purus ornare pellentesque sit amet et ipsum. Suspendisse imperdiet mi at felis aliquet, nec consectetur arcu dignissim. Sed vitae diam maximus, maximus diam ac, scelerisque mi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morbi sit amet turpis a purus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Etiam tempor ultricies mi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maecenas auctor enim a volutpat mattis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sed urna justo, scelerisque consectetur pharetra vitae&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nam nec augue vel nisl placerat faucibus. Donec congue &lt;strong&gt;nulla quis nunc&lt;/strong&gt; sagittis placerat. Pellentesque non tincidunt velit, cursus porttitor tellus. Suspendisse pulvinar tortor at &lt;em&gt;augue aliquam sagittis&lt;/em&gt;. Duis non pulvinar augue. Ut tristique dignissim ligula, eget tempus diam molestie non. Nulla ultrices eleifend rutrum. Mauris convallis sollicitudin dui, pulvinar suscipit velit. Maecenas viverra finibus metus vitae blandit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pellentesque consectetur facilisis venenatis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nam ullamcorper, orci nec tempor hendrerit, lorem nunc laoreet diam, vel gravida sem mi quis augue. Nunc odio velit, facilisis quis dictum non, facilisis quis felis. Vivamus &lt;a href=&quot;https://google.com&quot;&gt;elementum dapibus nibh&lt;/a&gt;, eget aliquet nunc luctus maximus. Sed finibus risus eget ultrices maximus. Aliquam commodo consectetur diam eget tristique. Nunc quis erat quis felis fringilla tempus. Cras tempor nibh dolor, ac lacinia lacus ultrices eu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quisque tempor nulla turpis, ut placerat arcu lobortis nec. Aenean sed vehicula nisi. Nullam vitae placerat enim. Etiam hendrerit enim vel tempor fermentum. Morbi rutrum euismod ipsum a luctus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morbi et libero id metus tempor imperdiet eget non mi. Mauris pulvinar quis enim at placerat. Vestibulum vitae dapibus lectus, ut elementum est.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pellentesque facilisis venenatis mi, sit amet molestie nisl ornare et&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morbi posuere facilisis eros vel euismod. Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Etiam malesuada dapibus dolor non cursus. Sed in turpis justo. Cras sed hendrerit nulla. Sed ornare, leo et suscipit tincidunt, justo diam sollicitudin risus, vitae vulputate nulla augue et lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Morbi posuere facilisis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Etiam malesuada dapibus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ut vel ligula ante. Proin quis metus magna. Nulla nec dui vulputate, semper orci in, sagittis dolor. Mauris dictum neque non fermentum consectetur. Integer vel pellentesque ex, ut tincidunt quam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Sed ac orci a dolor venenatis vulputate&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sed sollicitudin, turpis ac malesuada dapibus, magna dui semper orci, in congue justo felis quis ante. Phasellus consequat et dolor fringilla accumsan. Pellentesque ullamcorper porttitor dolor et imperdiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;./space.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Space&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque consectetur facilisis venenatis. Nam ullamcorper, orci nec tempor hendrerit, lorem nunc laoreet diam, vel gravida sem mi quis augue. Nunc odio velit, facilisis quis dictum non, facilisis quis felis. Vivamus elementum dapibus nibh, eget aliquet nunc luctus maximus. Sed finibus risus eget ultrices maximus. Aliquam commodo consectetur diam eget tristique. Nunc quis erat quis felis fringilla tempus. Cras tempor nibh dolor, ac lacinia lacus ultrices eu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Nulla nec dui vulputate, semper orci in, sagittis dolor&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mauris dictum neque non fermentum consectetur. Integer vel pellentesque ex, ut tincidunt quam. Sed ac orci a dolor venenatis vulputate. Sed sollicitudin, turpis ac malesuada dapibus, magna dui semper orci, in congue justo felis quis ante. Phasellus consequat et dolor fringilla accumsan. Pellentesque ullamcorper porttitor dolor et imperdiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;document&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;ready&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    console&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;More jQuery, wow!&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;ras aliquet ipsum ut enim pellentesque, id varius quam placerat&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maecenas non scelerisque leo. Sed id purus fringilla, consequat magna non, faucibus neque. Cras ornare nisi a lectus ultricies convallis. Integer tristique dictum eros, et elementum ante consectetur eget. Phasellus sollicitudin est vestibulum suscipit pellentesque. Duis in eros cursus magna laoreet aliquam vel a lectus. Nulla ut nisi vitae ipsum sollicitudin vestibulum. Aenean sit amet mattis odio. Vestibulum ultrices sed ipsum nec pretium. Integer non turpis nunc. Praesent tincidunt tincidunt alique&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integer mollis dolor non libero placerat, ut efficitur nisi ultricies. Etiam ac lacinia urna, eget ornare nunc. Suspendisse eget eros id turpis gravida semper. Duis ornare lorem et est pellentesque, quis rhoncus leo vestibulum. Nullam eu nulla ut elit rutrum iaculis. Cras a laoreet elit, in aliquet erat. Sed interdum varius posuere. Pellentesque eget luctus erat. Nam quis sem in ligula efficitur bibendum.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>